JANVIER MBILIZI

Rockville, MD. 20850 | Phone: 540-236-2223 | Email: janviermbilizi@gmail.com

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/janvier-mbilizi | Github: github.com/Janviermbilizi | Portfolio: janvier-mbilizi.herokuapp.com/

Professional Summary

Full Stack Web Developer educated at the University of Denver (DU) who has a passion for approaching programming challenges from different angles. Strengths include meeting deadlines, creativity, and working as a team to create meaningful web applications. Remains calm in fast-paced environments and uses my education and skill-set to solve problems or debug when code is not working as expected. Outside of Software Engineering, holds a Bachelor's degree in Geology and Mining and has worked as a Case Manager and Community Advocate serving hundreds of refugee and immigrant families across the Denver-metro and Shenandoah Valley area. Passionate about meeting clients needs, strives to adapt quickly, communicate effectively, and think critically; these strengths allow me to be a team player. Quick and dedicated learner who is hoping to become an asset to your company.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and limited Python.

Frameworks: front-end frameworks(Bootstrap, Materialize, Foundation, ReactJS), back-end frameworks(Node.js, Express.js)

Core Concepts: Databases (MySQL, MongoDB), Computer Science applied to JavaScript (Data structures, Algorithms), Deployment (Heroku, Github), Version Control (Git, GitLab), Quality Assurance (Writing Tests), Server Side Development (Node.js, Express.js, Security and Session Storage, User Authentication, and MERN Stack), CLI and proficiency with advanced electronics.

Projects

Traveler | Git Repository: https://github.com/Janviermbilizi/traveler | Link to Deployed Project: https://janviermbilizi.github.io/traveler/

- *Description of project:* Application that travelers can use to organize/prepare (with checklist) and get information(such as weather, nearest airport, attractions, and more) about the place they are visiting.
- *Core Responsibilities*: Full-Stack Development (designed the weather and checklist card, and made API calls that get data from weather API and display them in the card depending on the City or place that the user searched for)
- *Tools/Languages Used*: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, materialize CSS framework, Git/Github, and APIs (weather, Google Maps, AirportFinder, and Airport info got from Rapid API).

Metabook | Git Repository: https://github.com/cwright489/Project2 | Link to Deployed Project: https://cryptic-sea-06963.herokuapp.com/

- Description of project: Application that users can use to learn about themselves through zodiacs by entering basic information.
- Core Responsibilities: Full-Stack Development (Managed handlebars to display data coming from APIs)
- *Tools/Languages Used:* HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, handlebars, MySQL, Sequelize, Lodash.js, Passport.js, Express, Git/Github, Heroku, and Astrology API.

entertainME | Git Repository: https://github.com/Janviermbilizi/entertain-me | Link to Deployed Project: https://entertainme-app.herokuapp.com/

- Description of project: Application that allows the user to follow their favorite movies, TV shows, and celebrities all in one place. It allows the user to follow what interests them by favoriting and tracking new releases with the ability to share socially and see what others in the community are watching.
- Core responsibilities: Full-Stack Development(Authentification, User's profile, database management, general UI).
- *Tools/Languages Used:* HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MERN(MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js), framework(React-Materialize), npm packages(Bcrypt, Passport, express-jwt, Axios, etc...), APIs(The movie database or TMDB and randomuser)

Professional Experience

Full Stack Web Developer Student

University of Denver Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp

2019 - Current

Successfully Managed and worked in a team as a full-stack web developer for the creation of three full-stack projects

Case Manager

Lutheran Family Services (LFS), Denver CO

2018

Successfully managed, served and advocated for over two hundred refugee, asylee and immigrant families in the Denver-metro area, trained and managed interns throughout the year, and developed and analyzed reports.

Assistant Case Worker

Church World Service (CWS) Harrisonburg Refugee and Immigration Office, Harrisonburg, VA

2017 - 2018

Community Advocate successfully served hundreds of refugee, asylee and immigrant families across the Shenandoah Valley area.

Intern

National Building and Public Works Laboratory (LNBTP), Burundi/Africa

2016 - 2017

Successfully Analyzed and synthesized the geotechnic and rheumatic characteristics of materials. Developed and analyzed reports.

Education

Certification in Full Stack Web Development, University Of Denver (DU), Denver CO Bachelor of Science in Geology and Mining, University of Burundi (UB), Burundi

Leadership and Core Skills

-Vice President of CEG (Club of Geology students at the University of Burundi)

2013 - 2017

- Fluency in 6 languages including, French, Swahili, Kirundi, Kinyarwanda, Kinyamulenge, and Chinese(Mandarin).
- Public speaking, Interpreting, translating, and Community Advocate